export const COSTINGA2020 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. Which of the following describes Cost Accounting?",
A: "Cost reports are prepared annually",
B: "It is a legal requirement",
C: "It is for external use •only",
D: "It uses past, present and future information",
answer: "A. cost centres and cost units.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. Cost Accounting aims at increasing business profit by",
A: "controlling cost",
B: "controlling prices.",
C: "increasing cost",
D: "increasing sales",
answer: "A. control cost.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. In order for Cost Accounting system to be easily understood, it must be",
A: "cost effective",
B: "free from bias",
C: "relevant to the organization",
D: "simple to operate",
answer: "C. relevant to the organization",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. Late presentation of Cost Accounting information will affect its",
A: "Accuracy",
B: "Clarity",
C: "Simplicity",
D: "Usefulness",
answer: "D. Usefulness",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. Costs are classified according to",
A: "common basis",
B: "income and expenditure",
C: "common characteristics",
D: "profit or loss.",
answer: "C. common characteristics",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. Expenses incurred in searching for new or improved products is",
A: "administrative costs",
B: "distribution costs.",
C: "research and development costs",
D: "selling costs.",
answer: "C. research and development costs",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. The salary paid to a factory supervisor is",
A: "direct expenses.",
B: "direct labour cost.",
C: "indirect labour cost.",
D: "indirect expenses.",
answer: "C. indirect labour cost.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. Grouping of costs into materials, labour and expenses is classification by",
A: "behaviour",
B: "function",
C: "nature",
D: "normality",
answer: "C. nature",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. The system where stock records are adjusted after every purchase or sale is",
A: "continuous stocktaking",
B: "inventory control",
C: "periodic stocking",
D: "perpetual inventory",
answer: "D. perpetual inventory",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. Economic Order Quantity is the",
A: "Average amount of materials to be ordered.",
B: "Minimum amount of materials to be ordered.",
C: "maximum amount of materials to be ordered.",
D: "Optimum amount of materials to be ordered",
answer: "D. Optimum amount of materials to be ordered",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. The purpose of pricing issues from stores is to determine",
A: "cost of material is is used",
B: "quantity of closing stock.",
C: "quantity of materials issued.",
D: "selling price of goods.",
answer: "A.  cost of material is is used",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. Material requisition note is prepared by",
A: "Accounts department.",
B: "User department.",
C: "Purchases department.",
D: "Stores department",
answer: "B. User department.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. Cost of materials issued using simple average method of pricing issues is",
A: "GH¢4,800.",
B: "GH¢ 5,000.",
C: "GH¢5,100.",
D: "GH¢ 5,250",
answer: "B. GH¢ 5,000.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. Cost of materials issued using weighted average method of pricing issues is",
A: "GH¢ 4,750",
B: "GH¢ 5,000.",
C: "GH¢ 5,100.",
D: "GH¢ 5,200.",
answer: "D. GH¢ 5,200",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. The value of closing stock using weighted average method of pricing issues is",
A: "GH¢ 900.",
B: "GH¢ 1,000.",
C: "GH¢ 1,050.",
D: "GH¢ 1,200",
answer: "B. GH¢ 1,000.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. Guaranteed wages are the",
A: "minimum amount to be paid to workers.",
B: "maximum amount to be paid to workers.",
C: "payment based on the units produced.",
D: "payment based on time saved.",
answer: "A.  minimum amount to be paid to workers.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. The period where workers are paid for not working due to machine break down is",
A: "idle time.",
B: "lead time.",
C: "overtime.",
D: "time rate.",
answer: "A.  idle time.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. An incentive scheme that encourages workers to produce extra units is",
A: "differential piece rate.",
B: "high day work.",
C: "premium bonus.",
D: "overtime premium.",
answer: "C.  premium bonus.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. Appiah’s basic wage for April 2020 is",
A: "D 1,875.",
B: "D 1,500.",
C: "D 1,320.",
D: "D 1,200",
answer: "B.  D 1,500.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. Appiah’s total earnings for April 2020 is",
A: "D 1,875.",
B: "D 1,575.",
C: "D 1,500.",
D: "D 1,250.",
answer: "A.  D 1,875.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. Total amount spent on Appiah by his employers for April 2020 is",
A: "D 1,875.",
B: "D 1,695.",
C: "D 1,595.",
D: "D 1,320",
answer: "B.  D 1,695.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. Cost drivers are",
A: "activities that generate cost.",
B: "overhead based on activities.",
C: "pools in which costs are grouped.",
D: "processes that increase cost.",
answer: "A.  activities that generate cost.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. The charging of overheads to cost units is",
A: "absorption.",
B: "allocation.",
C: "apportionment.",
D: "distribution.",
answer: "A.  absorption.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. Over absorption of overheads occurs when actual overheads is",
A: "equal to absorbed overheads.",
B: "less than absorbed overheads.",
C: "more than absorbed overheads.",
D: "more than total overheads",
answer: "C. more than absorbed overheads.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. In a manufacturing company, service cost centre overheads are recovered by",
A: "charging to profit and• loss account.",
B: "absorbing using machine hour rate.",
C: "apportioning to production cost centres.",
D: "charging directly to finished goods account",
answer: "C. apportioning to production cost centres.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. Overhead absorbed into production is",
A: "Le 600,000.",
B: "Le 563,000.",
C: "Le 300,000.",
D: "Le 281 ,500",
answer: "A.  Le 600,000.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. The use of predetermined overhead absorption rate resulted in",
A: "over absorption of Le 281 ,500.",
B: "over absorption of Le 18,500.",
C: "under absorption of Le 18,500.",
D: "under absorption of Le 281,500.",
answer: "C. under absorption of Le 18,500.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. When customer orders a quantity of similar items which is produced to his specification, it is produced as a",
A: "batch.",
B: "contract.",
C: "job.",
D: "process",
answer: "A.  batch.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. What method will a textile manufacturing firm use in its product costing?",
A: "Batching costing",
B: "Job costing",
C: "Process costing",
D: "Service costing",
answer: "C. Process costing",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. Cost of work certified is",
A: "D 20,400.",
B: "D 239,900.",
C: "D 260,300.",
D: "D 280,700",
answer: "C.  D 260,300.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. Apparent profit on the contract is",
A: "D 20,400.",
B: "D 83,800.",
C: "D 104,200.",
D: "D 124,600",
answer: "B.  D 83,800.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. The contractor’s Account will be debited with an amount of",
A: "D 239,900.",
B: "D 260,300.",
C: "D 280,700.",
D: "D 364,500.",
answer: "B. period cost.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. In absorption costing, fixed manufacturing costs are treated as",
A: "period cost.",
B: "product cost.",
C: "relevant cost.",
D: "sunk cost",
answer: "A.  fixed overheads.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. The excess of total contribution over fixed cost is",
A: "breakeven point.",
B: "net loss.",
C: "net profit.",
D: "net sales.",
answer: "C. net profit.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. Variable cost per unit is",
A: "le 40.",
B: "le 48.",
C: "Le 55.",
D: "Le 66.",
answer: "A.  le 40. ",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. Gross profit using marginal costing approach is",
A: "Le 200,000.",
B: "Le 50,000.",
C: "Le 60,000.",
D: "Le 490,000",
answer: "C. Le 60,000.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. Closing stock under marginal costing is valued at",
A: "Le 42,000.",
B: "Le 50,000.",
C: "Le 80,000.",
D: "Le 110,000",
answer: "C. Le 80,000.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. The time frame within which the budget is to be used is",
A: "budget manual.",
B: "budget period.",
C: "functional budget.",
D: "key factor.",
answer: "B. budget period.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. The key factor in the preparation of the cash budget is",
A: "availability of funds.",
B: "depreciation charges.",
C: "payment for purchases.",
D: "profit on disposal of assets",
answer: "A. availability of funds.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. A type of budget that is designed to change with the level of activity is",
A: "sales budget.",
B: "flexible budget.",
C: "fixed budget.",
D: "production budget.",
answer: "B. flexible budget.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question41",
question:  "41. Production for December is",
A: "2,500 units.",
B: "3,000 units.",
C: "5,500 units.",
D: "6,000 units.",
answer: "C. 5,000 units.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question42",
question:  "42. Production for January is",
A: "2,500 units.",
B: "3,000 units.",
C: "5,000 units.",
D: "6,000 units",
answer: "B. 3,000 units.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question43",
question:  "43. Standards that are set for use over a short period is",
A: "attainable standard.",
B: "current standard.",
C: "basic standard.",
D: "ideal standard",
answer: "B. current standard.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question44",
question:  "44. Management’s perception of the expected performance is",
A: "budget.",
B: "forecast.",
C: "standard.",
D: "variance.",
answer: "B. forecast.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question45",
question:  "45. Actual price per kg is",
A: "GH¢3.",
B: "GH¢ 8.",
C: "GH¢9.",
D: "GH¢ 10",
answer: "A.  GH¢3. ",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question46",
question:  "46. Standard quantity for actual production is",
A: "101,200 kg.",
B: "113,80 kg.",
C: "253,000 kg.",
D: "910,800 kg.",
answer: "A.  101,200 kg.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question47",
question:  "47. Material price variance is",
A: "GH¢ 227,700.",
B: "GH¢ 37,950",
C: "GH¢ 37,950",
D: "GH¢ 227,700",
answer: "C. GH¢ 37,950",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question48",
question:  "48. The system of Cost Accounts which has no double entry link with financial Accounts is",
A: "absorption costing",
B: "activity based costing",
C: "integrated cost accounts.",
D: "interlocking cost accounts",
answer: "D. interlocking cost accounts",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question49",
question:  "49. One item that reduces the costing profit as compared to financial accounting profit is",
A: "depreciation.",
B: "discount allowed.",
C: "imputed rent payable.",
D: "loss on disposal of assets",
answer: "C. imputed rent payable.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question50",
question:  "50. Materials returned to suppliers is debited to Cost Ledger Control Account and credited to",
A: "Stores Ledger Control Account.",
B: "Work in Progress Control Account.",
C: "Materials Control Account.",
D: "Suppliers Control Account.",
answer: "D. Suppliers Control Account.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},


]